Scott Zhou

Senior Software Engineer at Ericsson

Bergåsstigen 2F 182 33 DANDERYD, Sweden +46 72 53 98 656 scott.cong.zhou@gmail.com www.scottzhou.me Skype: scott.zhoucong

SUMMARY

I am a software developer expert with 10 years' experience on software development and strong test sense, mainly focus on Python, C++ and Java. I have strong Linux server side application development skill, experience in data struct, algorithm, real-time media transport, Inter-Process Communication, multithreaded. I am a good team player with good understanding of Agile software development practices. I like to take responsibility, always been self-motivated and make things happen. The last and very important point about me, I have very good learning ability and always want to explore new things.

EXPERIENCE

Ericsson, Stockholm — Senior Software Developer

SEPTEMBER 2009 - PRESENT

Take designer and tester role at product CBA Core Middleware, IMS node MTAS and MGC.

iSoftstone, Shanghai — Senior Software Engineer

DECEMBER 2007 - AUGUST 2009

Work as a consultant for Ericsson project.

UD Technology, Shanghai — Senior Software Engineer

JANUARY 2005 - DECEMBER 2007

Work for VAP and media server, in charge of real-time media transport.

NewTone, Shanghai — Software Engineer

AUGUST 2003 - DECEMBER 2004

Work for OpenSN Multimedia Telecommunication Application Server.

SKILLS

Python, C++, Java
Linux, multi-thread, IPC
TCP/IP, RTP/RTCP
Object-oriented design
Agile, Scrum, Kanban
Continuous integration and software testing
KVM, Cloud, Cluster
High Availability, Scaling
Telecom, IMS

AWARDS

Global cooperation

Exceeds Expectations Employee at Ericsson 2014 for product MTAS

Outstanding Contribution Award at UD Tech 2006 for product VAP

LANGUAGES

English: Excellent

Chinese Mandarin: Native

Swedish: Beginner

EDUCATION

Guilin University of Electronic Technology, China — Bachelor degree

SEPTEMBER 1999 - JULY 2003 Computer Science

PROJECTS

CBA Core Middleware — *Developer* october 2014 - PRESENT

CBA(Component Based Architecture) is an implementation of EAG(Ericsson Architecture Guide). Core Middleware is a component of CBA and it implements a number of services specified by SAF (Service Availability Forum). It is based on the third party open source product OpenSAF and provide high availability and scalable distributed software infrastructure.

- Expert on Core Middleware Scaling function, adapt Core Middleware to Cloud/Virtualization environment.
- Participated in Core Middleware software package schema definition and deliver the implementation for Software Management module.
- Facilitate creating virtualization test environment for engineer to improve develop effectiveness.

IMS MTAS — *Designer and Tester* DECEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2014

The Multimedia Telecommunication Application Server is an application server located on the ISC interface in an IMS network. Its purpose is to provide real time peer-to-peer communication services.

- Work in Agile WoW and be cross-functionally, can take both developer and tester tasks.
- Work in ST AS (SIP Trunking Application Server) responsible team, provide support towards internal and external in ST AS function area.

IMS MGC — *Designer* DECEMBER 2007 - NOVEMBER 2011

Media Gateway Controller is the node provides signaling level interworking function between circuit switched telephone network, GSTN and packet switched multimedia networks.

- Support issues from external customer site and bug fix.
- Analysis customer requirement and write implement propose.
- Design and implement session trace mechanism.

IP Value-add Application Platform (VAP) — *Designer* JANUARY 2005 - DECEMBER 2007

VAP is a VoIP development platform, providing C++ API. Based on the platform customers can be develop their own IP-based value-add application quickly and easily. VAP isolates the media and SIP signaling details, developers who use VAP can focus on their business logic. VAP use SIP as control signaling, RTP/RTCP for media transmission, and support G.723, G.729, G.711, G.726 voice protocol.

- Contribute to VAP software architecture definition based on the limited hardware environment.
- In charge of real-time media transport module in the VAP Media Server base on 3rd party RTP/RTCP and codec library.
- Develop and deliver SIP base commercial applications based on VAP.

OPEN SOURCE

OPEN SAF

Core Middleware use OpenSAF to provide service availability function. Ericsson is the founder of this project and provide continually contribution to OpenSAF. I worked on implementation code and provide test on OpenSAF inside in Ericsson.

JRTPLIB

VAP (the product when I working for UD technology) use jrtplib as the RTP stack. I integrated jrtplib into VAP product.

LIB SHM TABLE

Lib_shm_talbe implements a hash or sorted table in Shared Memory (POSIX standard) to provide best access time. It can be used as cache between different processes.

JEDY

Jedy is a JVM (Java SE 8 Edition) implementation on Python3, it can execute some simple java classfiles now and continuing evolving.

OTHERS

Please visit my Github homepage (https://github.com/scott-zhou) for detail informations about my personal open source project. Coding is interesting thing and I love to share my codes with the world.

- Lib-log, asynchronous log/trace library. (C++)
- Broadcast chat server, a simple chat server implemented in Erlang.
- Top stock treading, a python script to download the top trading stock history from web and export into a csv file.
- Personal homepage, implemented in Ruby on Rails.
- ViKan, Virtual Kanban board web application implemented by JavaScript.